

Personal Information

- A problem-solver with an MSc in Economics and 4+ years of turning analytics into strategy. Designed end-to-end BI reports (Fabric, PBI) to unify data from diverse sources, optimize workflows and implement DMAIC insights.
- I'm ready to channel my track record in agile analytics delivering up to 75% error reduction and 30% lead-time improvements-into Dreamdata's enterprise clients always prioritizing their success in maximizing the impact of their marketing efforts.
- I'm a minded explorer just as passionate about deep-diving into new cultures as I am about tackling coding challenges. Proof of that my GitHub profile, where I've tackled diverse end-to-end solutions. And I'd be glad to share this with the team.
- What previous managers say about me:

"Ener proved to be a self-starter, a persistent professional, a fast learner and great team member, delivering work in timely manner and with high-quality." - Andrea S. (Currently, Vice President Wind Energy Research, Rystad Energy).

* see my recommendations: & ener-hagi/recommendaitions

Work Experience



Odense Analytica

Odense, Denmark, August 2024 - Present

Data Analyst Full time - Hybrid

- Company: Early-stage consulting firm specializing in Power BI and Power Platform for Danish high-precision engineering firms. Manages four active clients, offering on-demand capacity, pre-built reports, and hypothesis testing with minimal disruption. Supported by SDU Research & Innovation Organization.
- Responsibilities: 1) Developed agile Power BI solutions for HVAC clients, using DMAIC for Lean Six Sigma to validate to test and validate Operational Performance and Life Cycle Analysis based on Lean/Six Sigma principles, minimizing disruption. 2) Achieved a 75% reduction in reporting errors and ensured compliance with Danish Extended Producer Responsibility (EPR) through interactive dashboards. 3) Aligned solutions with strategic goals by identifying critical data need, fostering long-term stakeholder collaboration.
- Software: Power BI (Power Query, DAX) | Excel | Power Platform (Dataverse) | Dynamics 365 F&O | DevOps | PowerPoint

the LEGO Group
Billund, Denmark, May 2023 - June 2024

Data Analytics EngineerFull time - Hybrid

- Company: Danish toy firm renowned for the iconic LEGO bricks and various themed building sets that are popular worldwide.
- Responsibilities: 1) Product owner for "EMF Virtual Factory", and "Monthly Deep Dive Analysis", integrating CI/CD processes with SAP BW/4HANA, Dataverse, Excel. 2) Streamlined mould qualification, capacity, and cost efficiency while driving lean processes across the global procurement. 3) Reduced lead times by 30% (achieving 95% on-time delivery), and a 20% quality improvement (reaching a 90% in-spec target).
- Software: Power BI (Power Query, DAX) | Excel | Power Platform (Dataverse) | SAP BW/4HANA | Jira Atlassian | PowerPoint

Work Experience



Power BI Consultant Full time - Hybrid

- Company: Danish-based IT consulting firm specializing in Microsoft Dynamics 365 Finance & Operations (F&O) and Power BI for highly regulated Danish manufacturing companies within consumer goods, industrial products, and HVAC.
- Responsibilities: 1) Led the development of embedded Power BI reports, automating workflows and unifying data from Microsoft Dynamics 365 F&O. Excel and SharePoint via REST APIs, OData, and SQL Server, 2) Addressed manufacturing, procurement. operational efficiency, and inventory optimization, cutting reporting by 30%, trimming procurement lead times by 20%, and lowering excess stock by 15%.
- Software: Power BI (Power Query, DAX) | Power Platform & Automate | Azure SQL (SQL Server Management Studio) | DevOps



Universal Robots Odense, Denmark, Nov 2020 - Nov 2021 Market Analyst Intern

Part time - On site

- Company: Leading robotic company, which manufactures and distributes collaborative robots cobots worldwide, driving productivity and efficiency mainly in manufacturing through automation.
- Responsibilities: 1) Architected Heatmap Analysis reports in Power BI for Switzerland, Austria, and Italy, revealing geographic and industry-specific demand. 2) Identified a 30% TAM shortfall in Italy, enabling data-driven FTE allocation and targeted market expansion. 3) Supported Market Outlook Updates and Labor Shortage Analysis, using Eurostat, national statistics, PoS and D&B data, addressing workforce reductions and aging demographics.
- Software: Power BI (Power Query, DAX) | Excel | PowerPoint

SDU Research Assistant in Health Economics Odense, Denmark. Sept 2020 - Sept 2021

Southern Denmark University

Part time - Hybrid

- Feature: A study project to determine the causality of the use of antidepressants (AD) over the socioeconomic variables in Denmark.
- Responsibilities: Executed ETL processes on Danmarks Statistik's (DST) private server using RStudio with R (utilizing SQL for database operations via dbplyr package, similar to PySpark for Apache Spark in Python). Processed yearly CSV files, harmonized multidimensional data, improved data integrity, and loaded the data into a star-schema database accessible via DST's Microsoft Virtual Desktop.
- Software: RStudio (SQL)

Education

Southern Denmark University

Odense, Denmark. Sept 2019 - Sept 2021

MSc. In Economics

- Two-year program with relevant courses such as Big Data and Applications, Industrial Organization, Advanced Economic Evaluation, and Micro-econometrics.
- Thesis: Developed a star-schema database to analyse antidepressant (AD) market trends and competitor performance in Denmark, evaluating alignment with WHO's 2030 depression diagnosis projections. Data sourced from Danmarks Statistik (DST).
- Key data project: Cost-Benefit Analysis of transitioning from conventional to EV cars in Denmark, quantifying financial benefits.
- Key data project: Monte-Carlo simulation on RStudio to test the causal effect of an instrumental variable on a dependent variable under stress scenarios for enhancing statistical business applications.

Complutense University of Madrid

Madrid, Spain. Sept 2012 - Feb 2017

Bachelor's Degree in Economics

- Four-years Bachelor's Degree with focus on market analysis. Utilized Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, and Econometrics to predict market response to shocks in demand and production, aligned with LEAN principles for production and supply chain.
- Key data project: Utilized ArcGIS for spatial analysis of FMCG companies across Spain, optimizing supply chain delivery by ensuring optimal lead time between cities and supplier locations. Data source: RCE and SABI.